基本准备好了
Okay. We're almost ready here.
好 滤镜别用得太过 小卡
Okay. Now, easy on the filters, Cam.
全家福而已 不要用什么复古色调
It's a family picture. We don't need sepia tone.
你知道什么色调[语调]不该用吗
You know what other tone we don't need?
友好一点
Play nice.
好吧
Okay.
我们要拍张新照片挂在壁炉上
We are taking a new photo for above our mantel.
现在挂的那张没有莉莉
Lily's not in the one up there now,
我们察觉到...这似乎让她有点...
and we...started to get the slight impression that...
不满意
it was bothering her.
莉莉 要吃晚饭啦 亲...
Lily, we're ready for dinner, sw--
笑得灿烂一点
Big smiles!
-太好了 -太好了
- Great. - Great.
来看看
Let's take a look.
还不错
Okay. Not bad.
Not bad.
-我们来抖下脸 -真的要吗
- Let's shake out our faces. - Really?
是谁在网上看了教学视频 快抖抖
Who took the online course? Shake 'em out.
可以了 非常好
Yep. That's perfect.
-茄...子... -茄...子...
- Chee-e-e-se! - Chee-e-e-se!
好了 很好
Okay. Great!
米奇尔
Okay, um, Mitchell,
-你能过来一下吗 -好
- can I see you over here, please? - Yeah.
等一下 亲爱的
Hang tight, sweetie.
你看
Look.
她的脸怎么那样
Why is she doing that with her face?
不知道 我从没见过
I don't know. I've never seen
这么怪异又勉强的笑脸
such a weird, forced smile.
我好看吗
How do I look?
-美死了 -好看极了
- Beautiful. - Perfect.
这校园太棒了
What an amazing campus!
看那些楼都超酷的
I mean, look at these cool buildings.
你们有看到乌龟吗
And did you guys see the turtles?
再看看这个
And check this out --
明镜般的池塘
A reflecting pond.
很好 你可以照照看你现在有多疯癫了
Great. Maybe you can see how crazy you're being right now.
天哪 我要是带飞盘来就好了
God, I wish I'd brought a frisbee.
这里有什么特别的吗
What's so special?
跟我之前上的大学一模一样啊
It looks exactly like the college I went to.
我们在这里的时间
And we've been here
也跟你在那里待的时间一样短
exactly as long as you were there.
卢克 别这么刻薄
Luke, be nice.
艾丽克斯要走了
Well, Alex is leaving.
总得有人继续毒舌传统吧
Somebody's got to keep the trains running.
支持我啊 各位
Back me up here, guys.
这地方太适合艾丽克斯了 对吧
This place screams "Alex," Right?
跟美国其他大学没什么区别啊
It looks like every other college in America.
有什么我没注意到的吗
What am I missing?
好成绩 SAT分数 基本语言能力
Good grades, S.A.T. scores, basic verbal skills.
学着点
That's how you do it.
加州理工学院真是棒极了
Caltech is the perfect school.
对克莱尔来说
For Claire.
还有艾丽克斯 拜托 我们说的可是
And Alex! Come on, we are talking about
全国最好的学校之一
one of the best schools in the country.
是的 离我们家是只有45分钟车程
And, yes, it happens to be 45 minutes from our house.
当然 她去哪儿我们都会支持她
Of course, we'll support her wherever she goes.
当然啦 对我来说 没什么
Obviously. Nothing is more important to me
比她的学业更重要
than her academic whatever,
但对于艾丽克斯
but with Alex,
最重要的是接下来四年
the important thing is keeping her close
要把她留在身边
for the next four years.
之后她要是去了海王星
After that, I'm never gonna see her
住在她建的生态馆里
unless she Skypes me from Neptune,
除非打视频电话 否则再也见不到她了
where she's living in a biodome she invented.
太棒了 那就可以去海王星过圣诞了
Awesome! That means Christmas on Neptune!
两年去一次好吗
Every other year?
不 不
No. No.
各位 请聚拢过来
All right, everyone, gather 'round.
我们马上要开始参观校园了
We'll be starting the tour in just a moment.
我要自己逛 去机器人实验室
Okay. I'm gonna peel off and hit the robotics lab
看看它们跟职业女性有多像
to see how close they are to a working female.
等等
Hold on.
没你想象的那么像
They're not nearly as close as you'd hope,
你不准离开我
and you're not leaving my side.
但很无聊啊
But it's so boring.
感觉像是在受罚
It's like I'm being punished.
你就是在受罚
You are being punished.
你老师告诉我你逃课
That's what happens when your teacher calls
你就得受罚
to tell me you cut class.
我很遗憾 我拍电影忘了时间
I'm sorry. I lost track of time making my movie.
《蜂鸟人》
Hummingbirdman --
一个每分钟心跳一千下的超级英雄
A superhero whose heart can beat a thousand times a minute.
但他有感情吗
But can it love?
你们看 学校里有个实验室
Check it -- there's a lab on campus
拿你做实验还给你50块钱
where they do experiments on you for 50 bucks.
对对对 我以前在学校里经常做这个
Oh, yeah. Yeah, I used to do a lot of these in college.
有时候是回答问题
Sometimes it's questions.
有时候往你身上插一堆装置
Sometimes they hook stuff up to you.
有时候是跟一只猴子一起玩耍
Sometimes it's just palling around with a monkey,
不知道为什么他们只奖励猴子不奖励我
wondering why they're rewarding him and not you.
听起来不错 你应该试试
Well, that sounds great. You should go do that.
我要去
I'll go.
只要不用剃毛什么的 我就参加
I'm up for it as long as they don't shave anything.
我很想赚这50块钱
Hey, I'd love the 50 bucks,
但我相信老妈希望我留下来
but I'm pretty sure mom wants me here.
没有 你可以去啊
No, I don't. You can go.
别装了
Oh, you can drop the act.
我知道你俩逼我来这里
I know you guys forced me to come here
就是要我学学艾丽克斯
so I can watch Alex
重新激发我上大学的梦想
and get all inspired by college again.
真的没有
We really didn't.
对啊 是你自己上车的
Yeah, you just got in the car.
我只准备了四份三明治
I only packed four sandwiches.
结婚纪念日快乐 杰
Happy anniversary, Jay!
我不喜欢你这样
I don't love this tableau.
这是歌洛莉亚给我的礼物吗
Is that Gloria's gift to me?
是什么
What is it?
不知道
I don't know.
你肯定知道 一看就知道礼物是谁包的
Sure you do. I can tell by the wrap job.
她折不出这样的角 曼尼
She can't make corners like this, Manny!
那只是因为她总是匆匆忙忙的
Only because she's always in such a hurry.
生活真有这么忙碌吗 连抽出20分钟
Is life so busy you can't take 20 minutes
找一把直尺好好包装礼物的时间都没有吗
to get out the straight-edge and wrap a gift anymore?
别这样 我对我给她的礼物不太有信心
Come on. I'm a little anxious about my gift for her.
如果能知道这礼物是
It would make me feel a lot better
电话购物来的我会不那么紧张
if I knew she phoned this one in.
抱歉 杰 只有时间会告诉你答案
Sorry, Jay. Only time will tell.
天哪
Oh, God.
是我一直想要的沛纳海手表是不是
It's that black Panerai watch I wanted, isn't it?!
跟我猜字谜时 你反应怎么就没这么快
Why can't you be this fast when I'm your charades partner?
好啊 亲爱的们
Hola, my loves!
假装没看到我 别让她进车库
You didn't see me. Keep her out of the garage.
我们要怎么办
What are we gonna do?
我去跟她谈谈
I'm gonna talk to her.
我给她拍了这么多年照片
I've been photographing her for years.
我们之间建立了关系
We have a relationship.
真的吗 对方人怎么样
Really? What's she like?
我是说职业关系
I mean a professional relationship.
我要告诉她
Look, I'm gonna tell her --
她的笑是挤出来的 看起来不自然
Her smile is forced, it's unnatural,
我们没拍出好看的照片 就绝不回家
and we're not going home until we get what we need.
我要吐槽两点
Couple of things --
首先我们在家 其次那很毒舌
we are home, and that's mean.
你有什么建议
What's your suggestion?
我们给她看照片
We show her the photos
让她自己发现她诡异的笑容
and let her discover her weird smile on her own.
好吧 好主意
Okay. That's good.
就像我录下了我们的橄榄球赛
I video our football games
好让我看出哪里做错了
so I can see what we're doing wrong.
我就是那样发现
That's how I figured out
粉蓝色风衣让我看起来没精神的
that powder-blue windbreaker washed me out so much.
谢天谢地 橄榄球队一定很庆幸吧
Oh, thank god. I'm sure the team appreciated that.
-莉莉亲爱的 你能过来一下 -好
- Lily, sweetheart, will you come here for a second? - Yep.
我们温柔点 好吗
Let's do this gently, okay?
亲爱的
Hi, sweetheart.
好了 大爸和我觉得
Okay. So, daddy and I thought
我们要一起看看这些
that we would look at these photos together,
到目前为止我们拍摄的照片
the pictures that we've taken so far,
看看我们能不能做出什么改变
and see if there's anything that we would do differently.
比如说 当我看到这张照片时
Like, okay, when I look at this photo,
我觉得 我可以站得更直一点
I think, "I could stand up straighter."
-是啊 -小卡你呢
- Yeah. - Cam?
好 我觉得我不该帅得
Okay. I think I could be
像演员瑞恩·高斯林一样
a little less "Ryan Gosling"
应该表现得普通一点
and a little more "Every man."
莉莉 你看见什么
Lily, is there anything that you see in yourself
想改变的地方了吗
that you would want to change here?
也许我们该再拍一张
Well, maybe we should just do one more?
真的吗 好
Really? Okay.
这张脸要补点粉
This might need a little powder.
杰
Uh, Jay?
你老婆在楼上
Your wife's upstairs.
你没必要再躲在车库里了
You don't have to hide in the garage anymore.
我不是在躲着
I'm not hiding.
关上门好吗
Close the door, will you?
你给她买的礼物有多糟糕啊
How bad is the gift you bought her?
我没给她买东西
I didn't buy her anything.
那真的太糟了
Bad idea.
有次我给了她一袋拥抱
I once gave her a bag full of hugs,
她明显更喜欢实物
and she definitely prefers stuff.
不是拥抱
It's not hugs.
那听起来像是我的风格吗
Does that sound like me?
我在陶艺课上给她做了点东西
I made her something in my pottery class.
你居然去上陶艺课
I can't believe you took a pottery class.
这家里不止你有艺术气质
You're not the only one around here with an artsy side.
我可以给她买件首饰
Yeah, I could've bought her another piece of jewelry,
但我想着 她也许更喜欢这个
but I thought, you know, she might like this a little more,
这是我倾注了心血的礼物
coming from the heart and all.
给我看看 是什么
Well, show it to me. What is it?
这是什么
What is it?
是只小兔子
It's a bunny.
我以前叫她兔兔
It used to be my nickname for her.
我们第一次约会时 她感冒了
On our first date, she had a cold,
经常吸鼻子
and she was sniffling a lot,
她的鼻子会很可爱地皱起来
and her nose would wrinkle up real cute --
就像小兔子一样
you know, like a bunny.
太有爱了
That's so sweet.
是啊 但那块表又大又华丽
Yeah, but that watch is big and gorgeous
而且死贵的
and costs big bucks.
我不能送她自制的东西 她...
I can't give her something handmade. I mean, she --
她不像你我这么感情细腻
She's not sensitive like you and me.
听我说
Listen to me.
我觉得你去了心灵的珠宝店
I think you went to the jewelry store inside here,
带回来了一块宝石
and you brought back a gem.
闭嘴
Knock it off.
你这么觉得吗
You think so?
她会喜欢的 这太完美了
She's gonna love it. It's perfect.
不算完美啦
Perfect? Nah.
但是帕布罗老师的确说我很有潜力
But teacher Pablo did say it shows great promise.
尾巴是最让我自豪的部分
And I am proud of the tail.
看看
Look at that.
不不 我说的是看
No, no, I said look.
对不起
Sorry.
这栋楼里住着本校的五位诺贝尔奖获得者
And this building is home to one of our five Nobel laureates
现在他们仍在这里教书
currently teaching here.
里面还有高电流
It also houses our high-current,
高稳定性的粒子加速器
high-stability particle accelerator.
行了 你得冷静点
Okay. You need to calm down.
这是参观校园
This is a college tour,
不是在演《奥普拉的最爱》
not Oprah's Favorite Things.
我只是被这学校震撼到了 你没有吗
I am just so impressed by this place. Aren't you?
当然啦
Of course I am.
这是全国最著名的科技院校之一
It's one of the most prestigious tech schools in the country.
但如果你非得知道
But if you must know,
我并不爱这所校园的一切
I don't love everything about it.
是什么 对了 吉祥物是海狸
What? Oh, the mascot's a beaver.
别担心 那些笑话会过时的
Don't worry. Those jokes will get old.
不会的 因为我不会来这里
No, they won't, because I'm not coming here.
说真的 我今天来参观的唯一原因就是
Honestly, the only reason I took this tour today
好让你别说我没有给这学校
is so you won't accuse me of
一个公平的机会
not giving it a fair shot.
你为什么不想来这里
Why wouldn't you want to go here?
难以置信你要逼我说出来
I can't believe you're making me say this...
这里离家太近了
It's too close to home.
我得离你们远点 好吗
I have to get away from you guys for a little bit, okay?
好了 我们去看看宿舍
All right. We're gonna check out the dorms.
父母们 跟孩子们道别吧
Parents, say goodbye to your children.
好
Okay.
我该走了
I should go.
妈妈 等等
Mom, wait!
亲爱的 没关系
Honey, it's okay.
我们有时候就是会心口不一
We all say things that we don't mean sometimes.
低血糖 我要三明治
Low blood sugar. I need my sandwich.
好
Yeah.
好了 请你们在这里等着
All right. You can please wait here,
实验稍后开始
and the experiment will begin shortly.
-好 谢谢 -不用
- Okay. Thank you. - Yeah.
你们觉得会是什么实验
What do you guys think this is gonna be?
我敢打赌他们会给我们看
I bet they'll show us those ink blots
像是两个女孩在接吻的墨迹
that always look like two girls kissing.
老鸟给你点建议
A little tip from an old pro --
他们可以给奶酪通电 所以...
They can electrify cheese, so...
瞧瞧那个
Hey, look at that.
别按
"Do not push."
你在干什么
What are you doing?
教教这按钮什么叫自由意志
Teaching this button a little something about free will.
卢克 上面写着"别按"
Luke, it says, "Do not push."
这让我更想按了
Which just makes me want to push it more.
海莉 帮我说句话
Haley, back me up.
按不按我都无所谓
Push it, don't push it. I don't care.
这镜子是不是有点怪 我看起来很模糊
Is this mirror weird? I look fuzzy.
谁会安一个按钮
Who puts up a button
然后贴个写着别按的标志啊
with a sign that says you can't push it?
正是那些暗中布局
The same people who stack the deck
好让猴子每次都赢的人
so the monkey always wins...
科学家们
Scientists!
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我们不是在等着做实验
We're not waiting for the experiment.
这就是实验
This is the experiment!
他们正看着我们呢
They're watching us right now!
等等 你说什么
Wait. What?
准备
And...
-好了 -我们来看看吧
- Okay. Good. - All right. Let's take a look.
真漂亮
Oh! Beautiful.
她看起来就像胡娇家的小博美
Okay. She looks like Pepper's pomeranian.
我们得说说她
We have to say something.
发生什么事了 怎么还没拍完啊
What's going on? Why are we still doing this?
宝贝 二爸和我觉得你是个漂亮的女孩
Honey, daddy and I think you are a beautiful girl
笑起来特别好看
with a beautiful smile.
谢谢
Thank you.
不用谢
You're welcome.
你现在就是这么好看
And I'm seeing that here, okay?
可是在照片上却没看出来
But I'm just not seeing it here.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
是这样的
Uh, well, uh...
莉莉 你今天笑起来不太自然
Lily, you're doing a different smile today.
怎么不自然了
Different how?
稍微有一点 僵硬
It's just a little... stiff.
很丑吗
Is it ugly?
一点也不丑
It's not ugly. No.
只是 只是
It's, uh -- it, um...
小卡
Cam...
是这样的 小宝贝
Uh, well, s-sweetie, um,
看起来跟你平常美美的笑容有点不同
it's just not your normal smile, which is so beautiful.
你是说我不美吗
You mean I'm not beautiful?
不 我们不是这个意思
No, that's not what we're saying.
算了吧 我不想再拍了
Just forget it! I don't want to do this anymore!
我是个丑八怪
I'm an ugly monster,
我要关在房间里永远不出门
and I'm never coming out of my room again!
好吧 我们搞砸了
Okay. Well, that was a disaster.
的确 可是我得说
Agreed. But can I just say
我好爱她那种超具戏剧性的气质
I love how melodramatic she's getting?
非常棒
So fantastic.
-那种贵妃范儿 -我同意
- The little... - I know.
你在这
There she is.
亲爱的 结婚纪念日快乐
Hi, mi amor. Happy anniversary!
你也是 亲爱的
Happy anniversary, honey.
我希望你喜欢这个
I hope you like this.
你给我买了什么
What did you get me?
你给我买的这是什么啊
老妈 那是个兔子
It's a bunny, mom.
边缘不是很光滑
It's a little rough around the edges,
但我希望你会喜欢我放在里面的东西
but I'm just hoping you'll love what I put into it.
你在里面放了东西啊
Oh, you put something inside?!
我不明白 这里面什么也没有
I don't get it. There's nothing inside.
那 那是因为
Yeah, that's, uh... 'cause, um...
那个白痴的珠宝商没把手链放进去
The damn stupid jeweler didn't put the bracelet in there.
是我超爱的那个玫瑰金带波纹的手链吗
The rose gold with the waves that I told you that I loved?
对 就是那个
Yeah. Yeah, that's the one.
杰
Jay.
没事的 曼尼
No, it's fine, Manny.
我现在就去那间店把它拿回来
I can run down to the store right now and get it.
白痴珠宝商
Stupid jeweler!
杰 别骂他
Ay, Jay, don't scream at him.
我相信这只是个无心之过
It was an honest mistake.
也许他心里
Yeah, in his heart,
还以为自己做的是正确的事情
he was probably trying to do the right thing.
经过密立根图书馆
And past the Millikan Library,
你会看到安耐克斯桥
You'll find the Bridge Annex,
正是在这个地方
which is also the same site
卡尔·D·安德森发现了...
That Carl D. Anderson discovered the...?
中子
Neutron.
其他人呢
Anyone else?
-正电子 -正电子
- Positron. - Positron.
正确
That's right.
1932年
In 1932...
8月2日
On August 2nd...
在3楼
On the third floor.
真的吗
Really?
我 我也不知道 我就是想赢过你
I-I don't know. Maybe I just wanted to win.
我叫詹森
I'm Jason.
我叫艾丽克斯
Alex.
这里是你的第一志愿吗
Is this your first-choice school?
不 其实我想去麻省理工
No, I'm thinking M.I.T..
真巧了
That's weird.
我家离那儿只有半小时
I live just half an hour from there.
这就是你想来这里的原因吧
Which explains why you want to go here.
我住在这儿 可是我想去东岸
I live here, and I want to go somewhere on the east coast.
真的 我倒想要离家近一点
Really? I'd love to be close to home.
周日一家人共进晚餐 不用自己洗衣服
Sunday dinners, laundry,
还能看着我弟弟 不让他毁了我的
make sure my brother doesn't mess with
手工上色的南北战争模型
my hand-painted civil war miniatures...
其实我并没有非常爱惜啦
which I don't cherish.
那你为什么不去麻省理工
So why not M.I.T.?
对于应用物理来说 这里的课程比较好
Well, for applied physics, this is the better program,
而且我不会根据离父母远还是近
and I'm not gonna make the biggest decision of my life
来做自己人生最重要的选择
based off where my parents live.
挺好的
Okay, then.
不好意思 我说的是不是太武断了
Sorry. Did that... sound judgey?
和漂亮的女孩子在一起我就不会说话
I'm not really good at talking to pretty girls.
我 我觉得我有点自闭症
I -- well, I have a touch of Asperger's.
其实我没有
No, I don't.
我这么说只是想吸引你的注意力
I just said that so you'd think I was interesting.
我只是 有点希望你能来这儿
I was... just sorta hoping you'd be going here.
真的吗
Really?
你是我妈派来的吧
Did my mother put you up to this?
你妈会派男孩子来和你调情吗
Does your mom tell boys to flirt with you?
你 你是在和我调情啊
Oh. You're -- you're -- you're flirting with me.
其实我一点都不惊讶
I mean, I don't mean to sound so surprised.
很多男孩子都会跟我调情
A lot of boys flirt with me.
没有很多 有一些
Not a lot. Some.
的确有一个有自闭症的
Actually, one of them has Asperger's.
他能告诉你你出生那天的天气
He could tell you the weather on the day you were born.
好吧 我不知道自己为什么要说这个
Okay. Well, I don't know why I said that.
关键是 我是单身 是我自己的选择
The point is, I am single, by my own choosing, so...
天啊
Oh, my god!
我没事 我没事 什么事都没有
I am fine! I'm fine! Everything's fine!
我必须按它
I have to push it.
我脑子里只想着要去按它
It's all I can think of.
让他按吧 管他呢
Just let him push it. Who cares?
谁都不许碰这个按钮
No one is touching this button!
你不明白吗
Don't you see?
这是一个性格测试
This is a test of character --
测试我们是有自控能力的那类人
to see if we're the kind of people with self-control
还是那种看到面前有芝士
or the kind who just grab at any piece of cheese
就会拿起来吃的人
that's put in front of them.
你难道就不想知道它能做什么吗
Don't you want to know what it does?
想知道它能做什么
"Want to know what it does"?
当然 我超级想
Of course I do. It's killing me.
但我更希望的是
But what I want more
你能遵守规则
is for you to learn to follow the rules.
你是不是又在说我逃课的事
Is this about me skipping class again?
你这么执着这事真的太奇怪了
It's weird how obsessed you are with that.
让我按按钮
Now let me push that button!
不行
No!
如果你连这个简单的测试都过不了
If you can't even pass a simple test,
怎么能进好大学
how are you ever gonna get in to a good college?
或者保住工作 我们只有一个地下室
Or hold down a job? We only have one basement.
等你的人生也降到谷底时
There's no place for you to move
你可就没地方去了
when your life bottoms out!
好伤人
Okay.
爸 我翘了那课
Dad, I cut that class
是因为我必须为我的电影拍最后一组镜头
because I had to get one last shot for my movie.
换你也会逃课的
You would've done the same thing.
我的天
Oh, my god!
你气的不是我
You're not mad at me.
你在气你自己 因为我跟你当年一样
You're mad at yourself because I'm just like you.
歪打正着
Total shot in the dark.
你说得对 我给你树了个坏榜样
You're right -- I set a terrible example for you.
没这回事 这榜样很好
No! It was awesome!
你以为史蒂夫·乔布斯有循规蹈矩吗
Do you think Steve Jobs followed every rule?
还有魔术大师道格·汉宁
Doug Henning?
说下去
Keep talking.
还有那个住在
What about that guy who lived in that town
不让人跳舞的镇里的人
where people weren't allowed to dance?
《浑身是劲》的主人公有遵规守纪吗
Did Footloose follow the rules?
他叫伦 完全不守规矩
His name was Ren, and he most certainly did not.
也许科学家找的就是这种人
Maybe that's what those scientists are looking for --
不墨守成规的人
Rebels!
知道么
You know what?
我才不管那些禽兽要找什么样的人
Who gives a hoot what those bastards want?
无意冒犯
No offense.
我们就要违反规则 就要按按钮
We're gonna break every rule, and we're pushing that button!
就是这样
Yeah!
离按钮远点
Back away from the button!
你这是干什么
What are you doing?
我这一生都在违反规定
I've been breaking the rules my entire life,
看看我落得什么下场
and look where it's gotten me.
住在爸妈家的地下室里
I live in my parents' basement!
我已经恨透了自己总是一事无成
I'm sick of being a failure at everything!
我的天
Oh, my god!
你气的不是我们
You're not mad at us.
你是气你自己
You're mad at yourself.
我就是这意思
That's what I'm saying!
你去哪了
Where were you?
安慰杰
Consoling Jay.
你砸碎的不只是那只兔子 女士
That bunny wasn't the only thing you shattered, lady.
你第一次跟杰约会的时候
When you first started dating him,
他给你取了什么昵称
what was his nickname for you?
性感裤裤
Sexy pants.
另外一个
The other one.
兔兔
Bunny.
所以他才把手链放到兔子里
Oh, so that's why he put the bracelet inside the bunny.
里面没有手链
There was no bracelet.
兔子就是礼物
The bunny was the present.
就这只吗
That?
他亲手做了送你的
He made it for you himself.
不是吧
No.
他在陶艺课上做的 上了好几周课呢
In a pottery class he's been taking for weeks.
不会吧
No!
结果你把它砸碎在台子上
And you smashed it on the counter.
他尴尬得都不敢告诉你实情
And he was too embarrassed to say anything.
不是吧
No!
不能这样
I can't take it!
胶水 快拿胶水来
Glue! Okay, give me glue!
我要胶水
I need glue!
快让我停下来
Make it stop!
海莉 把凳子放下
Haley, put down the chair.
为什么
Why should I?!
因为这越来越荒唐了
Because this is getting absurd,
被整屋科学家
and it's no fun being laughed at
和穿尿布的猴子嘲笑一点也不好玩
by a room full of scientists and a monkey in a diaper.
没错 我们必须按下按钮
Yeah! We need to push that button,
告诉那些臭学究我们不是胆小鬼
show those eggheads that we're not sheep!
不行 违反规定并不代表你是英雄
No! Breaking the rules doesn't make you a hero!
而是个傻瓜
It makes you a screw-up!
记住我说的 卢克
Take it from me, Luke --
一百万个退学学生里
One out of a million dropouts
才出一个史蒂夫·乔布斯
becomes Steve Jobs.
知道有多少人变成没工作的败类吗
Do you know who become losers with no jobs?
剩下的九万九千人
The other 99,000!
宝贝 你不是败类
Honey, you are not a loser.
得了吧
Oh, please.
你们对我的"期望"我都听到了
I hear the shots you all take at me.
我妹妹就要跟我读同一个年级了
I see my sister about to lap me
进的学校还是我做梦都进不了的
at a college that I would never be able to get into.
就连蠢成我这样的都知道
Even someone as dumb as me
我是个多没出息的人
can see that I'm a giant failure!
海莉 别说了 好吗
Haley, stop, okay?
海莉 我告诉你
Haley, let me tell you something --
你有自己的价值 能力和潜力
You have value, talent, and potential
是他们的测试衡量不出来的
that their tests can't measure.
没人在意你是否符合他们的要求
Who cares if you don't fit into their little box.
你在寻找适合自己的路
You're finding your way.
二十几岁的年纪就应该这样
That's what your 20s are for --
去尝试
to take chances...
去犯错 吃一堑长一智
to -- to make mistakes and to learn from them,
而你已经在吸取教训了
and you are learning from them.
你不按按钮就证明了这一点
The fact that you won't push this button proves that.
说得太暖心了 爸
That was really sweet, dad.
我居然还想
I can't believe I was gonna hit you
抡凳子砸你
over the head with that chair.
等等 所以我们不按按钮了吗
Wait. So now we're not pushing the button?
不按了 我们要支持海莉
No. We're supporting Haley.
你下半辈子都要支持[养着]她了
For the rest of your life.
说这话帮不上忙
That is not helpful.
我们要团结一心
We need to stick together.
我懂了
Oh, my god.
测试的目的原来是这个
That's what this test is.
它不在于到底
It's not about whether we push the button
按不按按钮
or don't push the button.
你们是想看我们是为此团结还是分裂
You want to find out if this unites us or divides us.
大家牵着手
Let's join hands
给这些狗娘养的
and send these sons of bitches
和臭猴子开开眼
and their filthy monkey a message!
感觉好好
Feels good.
等等
Wait a minute.
我们什么也不做的话他们怎么知道
How are they gonna know we're sending them a message
我们要他们好看
if we're not doing anything?
有道理
That's true.
我们必须按按钮
We have to hit that button.
完全尼玛的正确
Damn straight.
好嘞
Yeah.
谁开的
Who did that?
是我们
We did...
以一家人的名义
as a family.
你们没看到标志吗
Did you not see the sign?
现在空调关不掉了 我们还得叫人来
Now the A.C. won't shut off. We have to call a guy.
不好意思 这个...
Oh, I'm sorry. Is this...
如果...
What if, uh...
对 这满楼的科学家
Yeah, building full of scientists
没有一个想到按两下按钮试试
and no one thought to push the button twice.
请使用二号铅笔
Please use number 2 pencils.
后面是墙
Yeah, just wall.
这才是测试
So this is the...test.
我跟珠宝商说清楚了
I got that cleared up with the jeweler.
他尴尬死了
Boy, was he embarrassed.
这是什么
What's that?
是我的兔兔吗
Is that my bunny?
不 我是你的兔兔
No. I am your bunny.
杰 我不想要那只手链了
Jay, I don't want that bracelet anymore.
这是你送给我的最好的礼物
This is the most amazing gift you have ever given me.
真的吗 你喜欢吗
Really? You--you--you like it?
我爱死它了
I love it.
把它黏回去的过程中
And putting it back together
我意识到你为此倾注了多少心血
made me realize how much work you put into it.
说实话 全都在于细节
Well, it--it's all in the details, really.
兔子就在粘土之中
The bunny was in the clay.
我只需要把它摸索出来
I just had to find it.
现在看看我给你的礼物
Now I'm going to give you yours.
也是时候了
I think it's about that time.
这个是...
And this would be, um...
电影票制成的书签
A bookmark made of movie tickets
用的是我们看的第一场电影的票
from the first movie we ever saw together.
我很喜欢
I-I-I love it.
这是那种我从来不会给自己买的东西
It's the kind of thing I'd never get for myself.
从来不会
Ever.
我们应该一直互相送这种礼物
This is what we should always do for each other--
我们过于追求物质上的东西了
We get too caught up in--in material possessions.
我们拥有的东西太多了
Ah, we got too much stuff.
明天一早就把它退了
Return this first thing tomorrow.
我也要把我给你买的表退了
Yeah, and I'm gonna return the watch that I bought you.
晚饭好了
Dinner's ready!
那是我想要的那条玫瑰金色手链吗
So, is that the rose gold bracelet that I wanted?
真是件极好的珠宝
Dynamite piece of jewelry.
说起那表
And that watch--
是陶制的 有十天后备电源的那款吗
Is that the ceramic with the 10-day, uh, power reserve?
当然 那表看上去真性感
Of course. It's so sexy, that watch.
是啊 那种喷砂面
Yeah, the matte finish
不会像这只表一样反光让人看不清
doesn't always catch the sun and blind you like this one.
真巧 我倒喜欢手腕上戴着闪光的东西
It's so interesting, 'cause I love shiny things on my wrist.
看在老天的份上 收下礼物吧
Oh, for God sakes, just keep the stupid gifts.
喂
Hello?
是我
Hey, it's me.
我觉得我和小卡犯了个大错
I think Cam and I made a huge mistake.
我理解 恋爱虽易 婚姻不易
Oh, I get it. Marriage is tough.
深呼一口气
Just take a deep breath
到杂货店找个人调下情就好了
and go flirt with somebody at the grocery store.
不 是莉莉的事
No, about Lily.
我们想拍张新的全家福
We're trying to take this new family picture,
可她一直笑得很诡异
and she's doing this weird smile thing...
你们说什么了吗
And you said something?
假设 假设是小卡说的
Uh, well, let's--let's just say Cam did.
首先 每个小孩都会这样
First of all, all kids go through this.
该让你看看卢克三年级时
You should see every picture
他每张照片的样子
we have of Luke from third grade.
他看上去好像在打喷嚏 实在太可惜了
He looks like he's mid-sneeze, which is a shame,
因为那年我胸大很上镜
'cause I was having a great boob year.
你采取的什么措施
What did you do?
可能是因为当时吃的避孕药 但...
I think it might've been the birth control I was taking, but...
不 我是指卢克
No, come on. About Luke!
什么都没做 我们没采取任何措施
Oh! Nothing. We didn't do anything.
米奇尔 我要饱含爱意地告诉你
Mitchell, I say this with love,
早在你要做家长的时候
but when you became a parent,
我就知道这可能会成问题
I knew this was gonna be a problem for you
因为你爱掌控一切
'cause you like to control everything.
天啊 这句话要是不含爱意会是什么样
Good lord. What would that sound like without love?
总而言之 船到桥头自然直
Bottom line-- it's all gonna work itself out.
可如果你给她施压
But if you push her on it,
她与你也就渐行渐远
she's just gonna push you away.
天啊
Oh, my God.
感谢大家的到来
Thanks for coming, everybody.
正如你们所知 我们的录取率是8%
As you know, our acceptance rate is 8%,
在秋季我见到的每个人战胜了其他...
so in the fall, I look forward to seeing one out of...
必然不会有他
So...not him.
看来该道别了 要去麻省理工的人
Well, I guess this is it, M.I.T.
如果你到波士顿玩 记得找我...
Uh, when you visit Boston, look me up...
达令[亲爱的]
Darling.
好吧 甜心
Okay, sweetie.
那是我的姓 我叫詹森·达令
Uh, t-that's my last name-- Jason Darling.
原来如此 我叫艾丽克斯·邓菲
Oh, well, Alex Dunphy--
邓超的"邓"不是凳子的"凳"
"P-h" not "F",
王菲的"菲"不是"非诚勿扰"的"非"
"Y" not "E-e".
右耳旁一个"又" 草字头下...
"D-u-n-p-h"...
我话咋这么多
Why am I still talking?
好吧
All right.
再见
Bye.
原来你在这
There you are.
宝贝 很抱歉我之前一直逼你
Listen, honey, I am so sorry about pushing so hard earlier.
如果要问有谁能做出明智的
If anyone is able to make a smart decision
择校决定 那就是你了
about where to go to school, it's you.
哪怕那所学校远在
Even if that school is all the way
美国的另一头
on the other side of the country.
其实 这里有很多不错的地方
Actually, there's a lot to like here.
真的吗
Really?!
好极了
That's cool.
无所谓啦
Whatever.
我猜家里有这么一个人
I guess there's somebody around here
让她舍不得离开
she's not ready to say goodbye to.
他加我好友了
He friended me!
来吧 我们要给你看个东西
Okay, come on, we have something to show you.
是晚饭吗 还是说我的嘴太丑不能吃饭
Is it dinner, or is my mouth too ugly to put food in?
不是
Okay, no.
另外不要再这么说自己了
And please don't say things like that about yourself.
你们选了一张吗
You picked one?
当然了
We sure did,
很抱歉我们让你不开心了
and we're sorry we made you feel bad.
我们只是不习惯你的新笑容
We just weren't used to your new smile,
可现在我们爱死它啦
But now we are, and we love it!
是啊 照片美极了 你也美极了
Yes, it's beautiful, and you're beautiful,
我们不想改变[换掉]你身上的任何东西
and we don't want to change a single thing about you.
内裤除外
Except maybe your underpants.
这笑声是什么情况
Okay, where did that laugh come from?
不知道 但必须让她改
I don't know, but it's gotta go.